<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Sandhya Tripathi</title>
    <link>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sandhyat.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sandhyat.github.io/media/icon_hu3e3f1b1735a575f65ba86d4cadd72940_8460_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matching Electronic Health Records from different sources</title>
      <link>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An applied problem facing all areas of data science is harmonizing data sources. Joining data from multiple origins with unmapped and only partially overlapping features is a prerequisite to developing and testing robust, generalizable algorithms, especially in health care. This joining is usually resolved using meta-data, which may be unavailable or ambiguous in a large database. We design and evaluate methods for mapping features between databases independent of meta-data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where and What of WIC in Missouri: A thematic analysis</title>
      <link>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairness evaluation methods in clinical prediction model</title>
      <link>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/example-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sandhyat.github.io/project/example-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the much needed discussion about fairness, explainability and transparency of machine learning models, their application in high-impact clinical decision-making systems must be scrutinized. We consider a real-life example of risk estimation before surgery and investigate the potential for bias or unfairness of a variety of algorithms. Our approach creates transparent documentation of potential bias so that the users can apply the model carefully. We augment a model-card like analysis using propensity scores with a decision-tree based guide for clinicians that would identify predictable shortcomings of the model. In addition to functioning as a guide for users, we propose that it can guide the algorithm development and informatics team to focus on data sources and structures that can address these shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
